Now some of these things that we're going to look at will make a little bit more sense once we actually
现在，我们将要研究的其中一些事情一旦我们真正做到，就会变得更有意义
look at the graph.
看图。
But I just want to go over some of the basic words we need to know before we get into that description.
但我只是想回顾一下在我们进行描述之前我们需要知道的一些基本词汇。
So first one analysis or analysis is a noun analyze is the verb form analysis means you study something
所以第一个分析或分析是名词分析是动词形式分析意味着你研究一些东西
and then you decide what it could mean and you interpret it.
然后你决定它可能意味着什么并解释它。
You don't just look at it and say what's there.
你不只是看着它并说出那里有什么。
You look at it maybe say what's there and then ask yourself.
你看看它可能会说那里有什么，然后问自己。
So what does this tell me about the world.
那么这告诉我关于世界的什么。
What does this tell me about this topic.
这告诉我关于这个话题的什么。
Whatever it may be.
不管它可能是什么。
So analysis kind of means studying something more deeply thinking about something more deeply and telling
因此，分析意味着更深入地研究某事，更深入地思考某事并讲述
yourself or telling others what it actually means on a higher level.
你自己或告诉别人它在更高层次上的实际含义。
So you would look at data study data analyzed data and then hopefully come to a higher or better understanding
因此，您将查看数据研究数据分析数据，然后希望获得更高或更好的理解
of the topic or your own opinion maybe.
主题或您自己的意见。
OK.
好的。
Now fertility this might not make sense.
现在生育这可能没有意义。
Now why am I talking about this.
现在我为什么要谈论这个。
But this just means it's related to birth women giving birth.
但这只是意味着它与分娩妇女分娩有关。
We're going to look at a graph that shows fertility.
我们将看一个显示生育能力的图表。
That means the number of babies born.
这意味着出生婴儿的数量。
How many babies are born.
生了多少婴儿。
So when we hear things like fertility rate we're talking about usually how many children women give
所以当我们听到诸如生育率之类的事情时，我们通常谈论的是女性生了多少孩子
birth to maybe in a country maybe in a city.
出生在一个国家也许在一个城市。
What's the fertility rate.
生育率是多少。
And that's going to be an average case on average an average.
这将是一个平均的平均情况。
I think you know it in averages if you add them all together and divide by the total number you have
我想如果你把它们加在一起然后除以你拥有的总数，你就知道平均值了
the average fertility rate.
平均生育率。
OK trends now a trend is usually a way to talk about the direction that something is happening in.
好的趋势现在趋势通常是谈论某事正在发生的方向的一种方式。
Now one way to talk about a trend is to is to discuss fashion.
现在谈论趋势的一种方式是讨论时尚。
Oh very cool right now.
哦，现在很酷。
This is a trend.
这是一种趋势。
This is a trend but you could also talk about trends like this.
这是一种趋势，但您也可以谈论这样的趋势。
Well every summer maybe the price of this type of clothing gets more expensive and it happens every
好吧，每年夏天，这种衣服的价格可能会变得更贵，而且每
year.
年。
So it didn't just happen once.
所以它不只发生一次。
OK.
好的。
So that's a trend.
所以这是一个趋势。
So something happens on a more regular basis or happens more frequently or it's easy to predict that
因此，某些事情会更频繁地发生或更频繁地发生，或者很容易预测
it will happen again.
它会再次发生。
Usually we use this word.
通常我们使用这个词。
It's used also in the fashion sense too.
它也用于时尚感。
They're related but not exactly the same.
它们是相关的，但并不完全相同。
OK.
好的。
So analysis fertility by the way the opposite of fertility just to mention that quickly is mortality.
因此，通过与生育率相反的方式分析生育率，很快就会提到死亡率。
Mortality is related to the opposite of birth which is death.
死亡率与出生的对立面是死亡有关。
So if you ever hear someone say high mortality you're talking about a lot of people dying.
因此，如果您曾经听到有人说死亡率很高，那么您就是在谈论很多人正在死亡。
GDP per capita.
人均国内生产总值。
Now I guess you probably know GDP this is gross domestic product and this represents basically how wealthy
现在我想你可能知道 GDP 这是国内生产总值，这基本上代表了多么富有
a country is.
一个国家。
Sometimes you'll see GDP per capita.
有时你会看到人均 GDP。
Don't be confused.
不要混淆。
It's pretty simple actually.
其实很简单。
Let's imagine that let's imagine that in a year a country makes 1000 dollars.
让我们想象一下，让我们想象一个国家一年赚 1000 美元。
Let's say this country has 1000 people.
假设这个国家有 1000 人。
So the GDP per capita is 1.
所以人均GDP为1。
So basically all you do is you take the total GDP and you divide by the total number of people.
所以基本上你所做的就是用总GDP除以总人数。
Then you have the GDP per capita.
然后你有人均GDP。
So on average how much money does each person have in a year.
所以平均每个人一年有多少钱。
Basically that's GDP per capita.
基本上就是人均GDP。
And some people say it's not a good way to judge how much money people have because you could have five
有些人说这不是判断人们有多少钱的好方法，因为你可能有五个
people with billions of dollars and a million people with ten dollars.
拥有数十亿美元的人和拥有十亿美元的一百万人。
Right.
正确的。
So maybe not the best way to talk about how much money everybody has.
所以也许不是谈论每个人有多少钱的最佳方式。
But it's a it's a way to measure the wealth.
但这是衡量财富的一种方式。
You could say the wealth or status of a country's economy.
你可以说一个国家经济的财富或地位。
OK decline and drop.
OK 下降和下降。
Now if you see something going down there's less of something less money less people whatever it may
现在，如果你看到一些事情正在下降，那么不管它可能是什么，更少的钱更少的人
be.
是。
We often say there is a decline in that.
我们经常说那是下降的。
For example recently we've seen a decline in violence a decline in violence.
例如，最近我们看到暴力减少，暴力减少。
Violence means maybe crime where people get hurt.
暴力可能意味着人们受到伤害的犯罪。
OK.
好的。
Why.
为什么。
Oh maybe there I don't know.
哦，也许我不知道。
Maybe there are more police.
也许还有更多的警察。
Maybe that culture is changing.
也许这种文化正在改变。
Whatever it may be there is a decline in violence but that doesn't tell us how quickly that's happening
不管是什么，暴力都在减少，但这并不能告诉我们这种情况发生的速度有多快
it may be over 10 years unless we say how long that is we could say over a six year period there was
可能超过 10 年，除非我们说那是多长时间，我们可以说在 6 年的时间里
a major decline in violence.
暴力大幅下降。
OK.
好的。
If it's sudden though then we'll probably use the word drop and we might even say a sharp a sharp drop.
如果它是突然的，那么我们可能会使用下降这个词，我们甚至可能会说一个急剧下降。
It's if it's sudden if you look at a graph and it goes straight down sharp decline you could say that
如果你看图表是突然的，它直线下降，急剧下降，你可以说
or a sharp drop or a drop doesn't have to be over a period of time.
或急剧下降或下降不必持续一段时间。
It could be.
它可能是。
Well anything on a graph that goes like this you could say a sharp drop in the opposite of that would
好吧，图表上像这样的任何东西，你都可以说与之相反的急剧下降
be rise.
上升。
A sharp rise in crime a sharp rise in income.
犯罪率急剧上升，收入急剧上升。
How much money people make for example sharp suggests it looks like this.
人们赚了多少钱，例如夏普表明它看起来像这样。
The line in the graph looks like this.
图中的线如下所示。
So I think this will make more sense once we actually look at the graph.
因此，我认为一旦我们实际查看图表，这将更有意义。
Let's just take a look at it.
让我们来看看它。
Talk about what it means then we'll look at how we can actually describe it.
谈论它的含义，然后我们将看看我们如何实际描述它。